

Brian Mawira

Software Engineer

🔀 brianmawira2@gmail.com 📞 254712413243 💡 Nairobi, Kenya 🛗 27 Oct 1997

🏲 Kenyan 🚣 Male 床 Mawira in brian_mawira 🜘 RodgersX 🙇 brian_mawira

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

East African Data Handlers 🗗

2021 - present | Nairobi, Kenya

Software Engineer

Collaborated with the design and backend development team to build a financial management application that's projected to solve the is management of funds and cut down on costs significantly, while storing the selected useful user data on an SQL database (PostgreSQL). We built a mobile app using Flutter & Dart to support both Android and iOS users.

AleroGroup

2019 - 2021 | Nairobi, Kenya

Frontend Developer

Collaborated with the team members to build a School Administration system to reduce the paper work and effort it takes in school to enroll and schedule classes. It was also projected to reduce the chances of a mix up or students missing results due to human error or negligence. The main frameworks employed were VueJS & NuxtJS together with NodeJS & Express.

PROFILE

I've worked in software engineering for my 4-year career, and my commitment to critical thinking and attention to detail have gotten me to where I am today: a senior software engineer for East African Data Handlers. I have a passion for processes, and I'm an experienced team leader who typically manages 6 developers at any given time

EDUCATION

Bsc. Computer Science

2016 - 2021 | Nairobi, Kenya

Jomo Kenyatta University of Agriculture and Technology

I teamed up with my classmate to develop a web application that helps final/senior year students with their projects right from the beginning. The main objective was to automatically match students with suitable supervisors picked from a list of lecturers in their respective institutions. This was made possible by a matching algorithm. As an additional feature, we integrated an API that gets real time news and refreshes every few hours with new information related to technology.

SKILLS			
Mobile Development Flutter & Dart	• • • •	Web Development HTML, CSS & JavaScript	••••
Frontend Development Vuejs + Vuetify, Bootstrap	• • • •	Backend Development NodeJS and Express	••••
Relational Databases PostgreSQL, MySQL	• • • •	NoSQL Databases MongoDB	••••
Version Control Systems <i>Git</i> , <i>GitHub</i> & <i>GitLab</i>	• • • •		

★ REFERENCES

Paul Gatheru, *Project Manager*, East African Data Handlers pkgatheru@gmail.com, 254724538083

Stephanie Kirathe, *C.E.O*, AleroGroup stephaniekirathe@gmail.com, 254729245657

Joshua Kimbareeba, *Backend Developer*, AleroGroup joshuakimbareeba@gmail.com, 254790309898